准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
招聘
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
啊  大海
Ah, the sea
那么迷人  那么美妙
so fascinating, so wonderful
裤头村
在这我们能看到裤头村
Here we see Bikini Bottom
充满着生机
teeming with life
住着我最喜欢的生物之一
home of one of my favorite creatures
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
他当然住在菠萝里  傻瓜
Yes, of course he lives in a pineapple, you silly
今天是个重要日子  小蜗
Today's the big day, Gary
小蜗
你看我
Look at me
我没穿衣服
I'm naked
要为今天保持身体最佳状态  小蜗
Got to be in top physical condition for today, Gary
小蜗
我爱痛苦
我准备好了
I'm ready
加油  海绵宝宝
Go, SpongeBob
到了
There it is
有史以来最棒的提供饮食的餐厅
The finest eating establishment
ever established for eating
蟹堡王
蟹堡王  蟹黄堡之家
The Krusty Krab, home of the Krabby Patty
招聘
窗户上还贴着招聘广告
with a help wanted sign in the window
我多年以来都在梦想着这一刻
For years, I've been dreaming of this moment
我要直接进去
I'm going to go in there
一路正步走到经理面前
march straight to the manager
直视他
look him straight in the eye
跟他撂狠话
lay it on the line
我做不到
and I can't do this
派大星
Patrick
你这是想去哪
Where do you think you're going?
我只是
I was just
才不是
No, you're not
你要去蟹堡王  拿到那份工作
You're going to The Krusty Krab and get that job
我做不到  看不出来吗
I can't, don't you see?
我还不够好
I'm not good enough
是谁出生后的第一句话是
Whose first words were
我能为你点餐吗
"May I take your order?"
是我
Mine were
是谁在木工工厂里用牙签做出了锅铲
Who made a spatula out of toothpicks in wood shop?
是我
I did
谁
Who's--
谁是黄色带洞的大方块
Who's a big-yellow cube with holes?
是我
I am
谁准备好了
Who's ready?
我准备好了
I'm ready
谁准备好了
Who's ready?
我准备好了
I'm ready
谁准备好了
Who's ready?
我准备好了
I'm ready
失败者
不好了  是海绵宝宝
Oh, no, SpongeBob
入口
他会想要什么
What could he possibly want?
加油  海绵宝宝
Go, SpongeBob
海绵宝宝加油  祝自己加油
Go, SpongeBob, go, self
招聘
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
快啊  蟹老板
Hurry, Mr. Krabs
现在还来得及
before it's too late
我要跟你说
I got to tell you about--
申请上船  船长
Permission to come aboard, captain
我一生都在自我训练只为了这一天
I've been training my whole life for the day
能够加入蟹堡王团队
I can join the Krusty crew
现在我准备好了
and now I'm ready
那么  什么时候开始
So, uh, when do I start?
小子  看来你很容易晕船
Well, lad
it looks like you don't even have your sea legs
蟹老板  求你了
Mr. Krabs, please
我会证明我是个当厨师的好材料
I'll prove I'm fry cook material
去问章鱼哥  他会替我担保的
Ask Squidward, he'll vouch for me
他不行
No
小子  给你一个测试
Well, lad, we'll give you a test
如果你通过了就可以加入蟹堡王团队
and if you pass you'll be on the Krusty crew
出去给我找一个
Go out and fetch me a--
一个
a--
水动力锅铲
Hydrodynamic spatula
带左右铲配件和涡轮发动机
with port and starboard attachments and turbo drive
找不到就别回来
And don't come back till you get one
遵命  船长
Aye, aye, captain
一把水动力锅铲
One hydrodynamic spatula
带左右铲配件  涡轮发动机
with port and starboard attachments, turbo drive
马上就来  长官
coming right up, sir
加油
Carry on
我们再也见不着那旱鸭子了
We'll never see that lubber again
你好坏
You're terrible
水动力什么来着
A hydro what?
蟹堡王
请大家都注意点
Hey, hey, please
乘客请在座位上坐好
Passengers are to stay seated
请勿将鳍伸出窗外
and not put your fins out the windows
听起来像舱门打开的声音
That sounded like hatch doors
你闻到了吗
Do you smell it?
那味道  某种难闻的味道
That smell, a kind of smelly smell
这难闻的味道  味道又很难闻
A smelly smell that smells smelly
凤尾鱼
Anchovies
什么
What?
凤尾鱼
Anchovies
吃
Eat
此处点餐
求你们  求你们
Please, please
安静
Quiet
这种行为成何体统
Is this any way to behave?
吃
Eat
就不能体面一点
Can we show a little decency
整整齐齐地在收银台前面排好队吗
and form a neat
single-file line in front of the register?
吃
Eat
便宜货超市
便宜货超市  满足购铲需求
Barg'N-Mart, meeting all your spatula needs
蟹堡王
船上全体成员
All hands on deck
动作都快一点
Get your anchors out of your pants
我只要求你们排好队
One single-file line is all I ask
封住舱口  章鱼哥先生
Batten down the hatches, Mr. Squidward
船进水了  章鱼哥先生
We're taking on water, Mr. Squidward
我要妈妈  章鱼哥先生
I want my mommy, Mr. Squidward
锅铲  锅铲
Spatula, spatula
带左右铲的锅铲
Port and starboard attachments
救命
Help
有人落水了
Man overboard
快爬啊  章鱼哥先生
Climb, Mr. Squidward, climb
全都结束了
This is the end
再见了  章鱼哥先生
Good-bye, Mr. Squidward
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
申请上船  船长
Permission to come aboard, captain
有谁订购了锅铲吗
Did someone order a spatula?
没错  一个水动力锅铲
That's right, one hydrodynamic spatula
带左右铲的配件
with port and starboard attachments
也不要忘了涡轮发动机
and let's not forget the turbo drive
你们信不信他们库存只剩一个了
Would you believe they only had one in stock?
前往厨房
To the kitchen
有谁饿了吗
Who's hungry?
困扰你的事  困扰不了我
Things that bother you never bother me
此处点餐
我快乐无比
I'm as happy as pie
肉饼
活在阳光下  爱在月光里
Living in the sunlight, loving in the moonlight
美好时光常在
Having a wonderful time
虽然钱不多  但需求不大
Haven't got a lot, I don't need a lot
咖啡一毛就够
Coffee's only a dime
活在阳光下  爱在月光里
Living in the sunlight, loving in the moonlight
美好时光常在
Having a wonderful time
相信我的话  我的这一生
Just take it from me, I'm just as
十分无忧无虑
free as any daughter
我愿想随时  愿意想如何
I do what I like just when I
做我喜欢的事
like and how I love it
当我入晚年  愿长留于此
I'm right here to stay, when I'm old and gray
巅峰永久不退
I'll be right in my prime
活在阳光下  爱在月光里
Living in the sunlight, loving in the moonlight
美好时光常在
Having a wonderful time
这是我见过最强的快餐经营技能
That was the finest fast-foodsmanship I've ever seen
海绵宝宝先生
Mr. SquarePants
欢迎加入
Welcome aboard
海绵宝宝
可  可是蟹老板
But, but Mr. Krabs--
为海绵宝宝欢呼三声
Three cheers for SpongeBob
一二
Hip, hip--
万岁
Hooray
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs--
一二
Hip, hip--
万岁
Hooray
一二
Hip, hip--
万岁
Hooray
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs--
我要到我的岗位清点战利品了
I'll be in my quarters counting up the booty
早安  蟹堡王的员工们
Good morning, Krusty crew
你想要点什么  派大星
What would you like to order, Patrick?
来一份蟹黄堡
One Krabby Patty, please
什么
What?
蟹堡王
蟹老板  蟹老板
Mr. Krabs, Mr. Krabs
蟹老板  看看你新招的员工
Mr. Krabs, come see your new employee
美好时光常在
Having a wonderful time
鼓风机
你
吹
吸
橡树屋的茶点
分镜总监
分镜
翻译: 1440kHz
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
四个触手
Four stingers
我以前在哪见过这位
Where have I seen this before?
实地导览
找到了  陆地松鼠
Here it is, Land Squirrel
陆地松鼠
那只小松鼠有麻烦了
That little squirrel is in trouble
接招  你这低等蛤蜊
Take that, you sorry old clam
你需要学会礼貌
You need to learn some manners
你的样子马上就要难看得不得了了
You're about as ugly as homemade soup
万岁  陆地松鼠
Hooray, Land Squirrel
小心
Look out
坚持住  小松鼠
Hold on, little squirrel
你打得很有两下子  巨大蛤蜊
You have fought well, giant clam
准备好被打败吧
Prepare to be vanquished
原来我弄得开
I'm actually doing it
你的壳归我了
Your shell is mine
坚持住  小方块
Hold on there, little square dude
你也喜欢空手道
You like karate, too
那么  你叫什么名字
So, what's your name?
珊迪
Sandy
要怎么称呼你
So, what do you call yourself?
我是海绵宝宝
I'm SpongeBob
海绵宝宝  你可要瞧好了
Well, SpongeBob, take a gander at this
是吗
Oh, yeah?
瞧瞧这个
Watch this
我喜欢你  海绵宝宝
I like you, SpongeBob
我们之间的关系会紧密得不得了的
Well, we could be tighter than bark on a tree
我也喜欢你  珊迪
I like you too, Sandy
你头上戴的是什么
What is that on your head?
是空气头盔
That's my air helmet
我能试戴一下吗
May I try it on?
这可不行  我还要用它来呼吸
Heck no, I need it to breathe
我必须要空气
I got to have my air
我也一样
Me, too
我爱空气
I love air
空气可好了
Air is good
你认真的吗
No kidding?
空气是我的特色
Why, air is my middle name
空气越多就越好
The more air, the better
空气求之不得
Can't get enough air
那明天到我家来点茶和饼干怎么样
How about coming over tomorrow
for tea and cookies then?
珊迪的树屋
你在这里
可别迟到了
Don't be late
好  明天见
Okay, see you tomorrow
派大星
Patrick
空气是什么
What's air?
我刚碰见了这个女生
I just met this girl
她戴着顶装满空气的帽子
She wears a hat full of air
你是不是说她摆架子
Do you mean she "puts on airs"?
穿着空气
应该是吧
I guess so
那都是花俏话术
That's just fancy talk
如果你想要花俏  就这样伸出小拇指
If you want to be fancy hold your pinky up like this
伸得越高  你就越花俏
The higher you hold it, the fancier you are
这样如何
How's that?
再高点
Higher
这样吗
Like that?
这样才叫花俏
Now, that's fancy
他们就该叫你花俏宝宝
They should call you SpongeBob FancyPants
要记住
Remember
犹豫不决  就伸小指
When in doubt, pinky out
你能行的  海绵宝宝
You can do it, SpongeBob
我就在外面看你
I'll be watching
谢谢兄弟
Thanks, pal
有人吗
Hello?
你好  珊迪
Hiya, Sandy
是我  海绵宝宝
It's me, SpongeBob
先等一下
Hold on a sec
这就让你进来
I'll let you in
珊迪
Sandy
快开门
Open up
珊迪
Sandy
珊迪  事情非常不对劲
Sandy, something's gone terribly wrong
根本没有水在
There's no water in--
这
here
当然没有水了
Course there's no water
只有空气
Nothing but air
没有水
No water?
这压根不成问题  对吧
That ain't a problem, is it?
问题
Problem?
我对空气就是这个看法
That's how I like my air
没有水
With no water
那好吧
Well, all right
我做了德克萨斯茶和饼干
I made Texas tea and cookies
快进来吧
Well, come on in
这可不算进
That's not in
快进来
In
你这小家伙可真奇怪
You're a funny little dude
来吧  我来带你参观
Come on, I'll give you the grand tour
这就是我的私人空气罩
So this is my own private little air bubble
这里的空气是最干燥
This air is the driest--
最纯净
Purest--
最空气的空气  全海洋无可匹敌
Most airiest air in the whole sea
那边是我的小鸟洗澡池
Over there is my birdbath
那棵是我的橡树
And that's my oak tree
能给我提供更多空气
It provides me with extra air
这座穹顶是用强度最高的聚氨酯做的
This dome is made of the strongest polyurethane
所谓聚氨酯是塑料的高级说法
That's a fancy name for plastic
是不是很厉害啊
Ain't that just the bee's knees?
跟你说吧  运到这也不算容易事
Tell you what, weren't easy getting here neither
首先  我得把它抬到一艘大船上
First, I had to hitch it up to a big ol' boat
那是我的跑步机
That's my treadmill
我就靠那个保持最佳身材
That's how I stay in tiptop shape
来吧
Come on
一起喝茶吧
Let's have that tea now
小指  小指
Pinky, pinky
我给你带了一点鲜花
I brought you some flowers
送我的吗
For me?
太棒了
How sweet
你没事吧
You okay?
没事
Yes
我好得很
I'm okay
你要知道
You know
你可是来这参观的第一个海洋生物
you're the first sea critter to ever visit
我想象不到是为什么
I can't imagine why
能给你提供些什么东西吗
Can I get you anything?
水比较好
Water would be nice
我要把这些花插进花瓶里
I'm going to put these in a vase
慢慢来
Take your time
必须从这地方逃出去
I got to get out of here
我喜欢你  海绵宝宝
I like you, SpongeBob
我们之间的关系会紧密得不得了的
We could be tighter than bark on a tree
犹豫不决  就伸小指
When in doubt, pinky out
我不需要水
I don't need water
水是给懦夫的
Water is for quitters
我不需要
I don't need it
这些鲜花可真漂亮
Why, these flowers are just beautiful
插进装满冰水的花瓶就能活得更久了
They'll live much, much longer
in a vase full of ice-cold water
来自我介绍一下吧
So tell me about yourself
当一个海底生物肯定很迷人
It must be fascinating being a sea critter
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
饼干好了
There's the cookies
去去就回
Be right back
我不需要
I don't need it
我绝对不需要
I definitely don't need it
我不需要
I don't need it
我需要
I need it
不行  海绵宝宝
No, SpongeBob
千万不可以
No, no, no
住手
Stop
小指  小指
Pinky, pinky
我是个逃兵
I'm a quitter
你不能临阵脱逃
You can't leave now
会搞砸的
You'll blow it
空气不好  派大星
Air is not good, Patrick
空气不好
Air is not good
你这只是太害羞了
You're just being shy
放心  兄弟
Don't worry, buddy
你表现得很好
You're doing fine
我不会让你搞砸的
I won't let you blow
这
This--
这到底是什么鬼地方
What kind of place is this?
里面根本没有水
There's no water in here
我一直想跟你说
I tried to tell you
必须马上出去
We got to get out of here
你都搞砸了
You're doing it wrong
等等  不
Wait, no
我们必须出去
We've got to get out
来吃吧
Come and get it
你一定会喜欢上这
You're all going to like this--
好了  这样应该就行了
There, that ought to do it
需要水就早点说嘛
If you all needed water, you should have asked
为新朋友干杯
I propose a toast, to new friends
先等一下
Hold on a second
希望你们能喜欢浓茶
I hope you all like your tea strong
喝吧
Drink up